(ナルト)テメエは引っ込んでろ！
ソラは… オレが助ける！
You keep out of this!
I'll... save Sora!
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
I haven't learned "sadness" yet.
kanashimi wa mada oboerarezu
And I'm just starting to grasp "misery".
setsunasa wa ima tsukami hajimeta
Even this feeling I hold towards you.
anata e to idaku kono kanjou mo
Is now turning into "words".
ima kotoba ni wakatteku
Waking up from the dream of this unknown world.
michi naru sekai no yume kara mezamete
I spread these wings and fly.
kono hane wo hiroge tobi datsu
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Knowing I'll find the answer,
tsuki nuketara
If I pierce through it.
mitsukaru to shitte
if I break free,
furikiru hodo
From that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
My Friend
(フリド)フハハハハ…
本物の人柱力も ソラに脱帽か？
So Sora has impressed
the real Jinchuriki, huh?
(アスマ)ソラを元に戻せ。
Return Sora to normal.
(フリド)オレには もう何もできん。
There's nothing I can do now.
もうすぐ ソラははじけ
木ノ葉は滅びる。
Soon Sora will break loose
and the Hidden Leaf will be destroyed.
(アスマ)させるか！
止めてみろ！
I won't let that happen!
Try and stop him!
オレは 巻き添えは ごめんだからな。
No way am I getting mixed up in this...
逃がすか！
You're not getting away!
ソラ！
Sora!
おん出してやったぜ
九尾の野郎を！
I got rid of him...
I got rid of the Nine-Tails jerk...
お前の力を借りてな。
And I did it by borrowing your power...
今度は オレが お前に
力 貸してやっからよ。
This time I'll loan you my power...
遠慮すんじゃねえぞ！
Don't hold back!
ソラ！ いい加減 目さましやがれ！
Sora!
For crying out loud...
wake up already!
(サクラ)ナルト！
Naruto!
大丈夫？
You okay?!
しっかりして ナルト。 今 治療を。
Hang in there, Naruto.
I'll heal you now...
(シカマル)
チッ！ 治療してるヒマはねえぞ！
She doesn't have time
to be healing him!
サクラ 逃げろ！
Sakura! Get out of there!
(いの)みんな 逃げて！
Run, everyone!
(ヤマト)大丈夫か？ みんな。
Are you okay, guys?!
(いの)えぇ。
(リー)大丈夫です。
- Yeah...
- We're okay...
(リー)そういえば
サクラさんと ナルト君は…。
Come to think of it,
what about Sakura and Naruto?
ナルト！
サクラちゃん 大丈夫？
Naruto!
Sakura. You okay?!
うん。
よかった。
Y-Yeah...
That's good...
そんなことより ナルト アンタの治療…。
More importantly,
I need to heal you, Naruto!
オレの キズの回復の速さは➡
You, more than anyone,
サクラちゃんが いちばん
よく知ってるはずだってばよ。
should know how quickly
my wounds heal.
それより ソラのヤツを➡
Anyway, I'll get Sora back,
no matter what.
オレが ぜってえ連れ戻すから➡
アイツの治療を頼む。
Take care of his wounds...
ナルト…。
Naruto...
わかった。
Okay.
ソラ…。
Sora...
ナルト！
大丈夫！
- Naruto!
- I'll be okay!
サクラちゃんは みんなのところへ。
You get back to the others.
This is between Sora and me...
これは きっと
ソラとオレの問題なんだ。
うん…。
Right...
ハ～ッ!!
(いの)どうなの？
私の医療忍術じゃ治らないのよ。
How's it going?
My Medical Ninjutsu
can't heal it.
(ヤマト)やはりな…
サクラが ケガしたときと一緒だ。
Just as I thought...
It's like the time when you got hurt...
(サクラ)九尾のチャクラで傷を負うと
治りが遅いのよ。
It takes longer for wounds inflicted
by Nine-Tails Chakra to heal.
しばらくは 針を
刺したような痛みが続くと思うわ。
A sharp needle-like pain
will still linger on the wound.
(チョウジ)大丈夫だよ。
(キバ)じゃあ なんだよ！
I'll be okay.
So what then?!
今 ヤツを押さえられるのは
ナルトだけってことかよ！
Does that mean Naruto is
the only one who can control him?!
そういうことになるね。
(キバ)そんな！
That would seem to be the case.
No way!
ナルト君…。
Naruto...
あの時 オレが
確実に お前を倒しておけば➡
If I had made sure
I defeated you back then...
ソラは こんなことには…。
this wouldn't have happened to Sora.
(フリド)よかったじゃねえかよ…。
You should be glad.
ソラのオヤジを殺したのが
お前じゃなくてよ。
That you weren't the one
to kill Sora's father.
いいや オレだ。
今度は確実に お前を…。
No, It'll be me...
This time for sure I'll...
また火影の命令か？
Still on the Hokage's order?
違う!!
No!
オレが許せないんだ…
子供にあんなことをするお前を！
It's unforgivable!
I can't forgive you for doing that
to your own child!
親だ子だ 何を言ってる！
What's with all this parent
and child stuff you're talking about?
そんなもんで動くのかよ！
火ノ国ってヤツがよ!!
Will stuff like that change
the Land of Fire?
動かすことはない…
つなげていくんだ！
It won't change it.
It will make it come together.
わるいが オレは動かす！
この国を… 世界を!!
Sorry, but I'm going
to change this land! And the world!
そのためにも 玉が必要なんだ!!
In order to do that, a king is necessary!
You're wrong!
違う!!
違うのは そっちだろうが！
You're the one who's wrong!
(サイ)忍法 超獣偽画！
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll
クソ！ 何だ これ!?
Damn it! What's this?!
こんな夜中に
病院抜け出して散歩か？
You sneak out of the hospital
in the middle of the night for a stroll?
(サイ)里が騒がしく
寝つけなかったものですから。
I couldn't get to sleep with
the clamor in the village...
フッ… まあいい。 さてと…。
Oh, well.
Now then...
これで ゆっくり
お前と話ができるな… カズマ。
I can have a nice leisurely conversation
with you, Kazuma.
お前と話し合うことなんて
何もねえ！
I've got nothing to say to you.
ソラ～!!
Sora.
クッ…！ いってえな～！
That hurts!
Remember, Sora...
思い出せよ… ソラ！
オレたちが…
出会ったときのことを…！
Remember... when we first met...
お互い 間違って
やり合ったときのことを…。
Remember when we accidently
got into a scuffle with each other...
オレを
助けに来てくれたときのことを…。
Remember when you came to help me...
Sora...
((ソラ！ ソラ！
Sora.
Sora!
(ソラ!!))
クソ…！
Damn it...
オレたちは
最初から間違ってたんだ。
We were mistaken from the start.
(アスマ)そもそも玉が
何を指すかというところからな。
Mistaken about what a king
refers to in the first place.
間違っちゃいねえ…
間違っちゃいねえんだよ アスマ!!
We weren't mistaken.
We weren't mistaken, Asuma!
If I...
オレが… オレが死んだら➡
If I die... what will happen
to the Land of Fire?
どうなるんだよ… 火ノ国は…。
Nothing will happen.
どうにもなんねえよ。
That's funny...
笑っちまうな…。
I don't remember my dad's face
very well.
((ソラ : 父さんの顔は
よく覚えちゃいねえ。
But even now, I can never forget
that spotless clean breechcloth.
ただ あの染みひとつない
きれいな腰布のことは➡
今でも忘れることはできねえ。
To me, my dad is that clean white cloth.
(オレにとって 父さんは
あの白い輝きそのものなんだ))
カズマ… お前の義は…。
Kazuma... Your cause was...
ソラ！
Sora!
((ソラ！
誰だ？
Sora.
Who's that?!
ソラ！
Sora.
なんだ ナルトか…。
Oh, it's Naruto...
Let's just calm down now and...
ここは落ち着いて… うっ！
話し合いで…。
Let's discuss this...
Hey!
You're hitting me with your punches!
こら！ お前のパンチが
当たってるんだよ！
ったく コイツは騒がしくて…。
Man, this guy's so loud...
大丈夫か？ ソラ。
You okay... Sora?
ナルト!?
Naruto...!
テメエ なに でしゃばって
来やがった！
You jerk! What're you doing
sticking your nose in this?!
来ちまったもんは
しようがねえだろ。
As long as I'm here,
I have no choice.
でしゃばりで…。
He's so meddlesome...
なぁ！ 何があったんだよ ソラ！
Hey, what happened, Sora?
お前と アスマ先生の間に 何が!?
離せ この野郎！
What happened between
you and Asuma Sensei?!
Let go of me, you jerk!
(うっとうしい野郎だぜ))
Such an annoyance.
今度は何!?
What is it now?!
いったい 何が始まるんです？
What in the world is happening up here?
これは…！
This must be...
ヤマト隊長！ ナルトのときとは
ソラの様子が違います！
Captain Yamato!
Sora is acting different from Naruto...
そうだね。
これは あくまで ボクの考えだが➡
That's right.
This is just a theory,
九尾のチャクラを とどめておくには➡
but I don't think Sora has the capacity
to house the Nine-Tails Chakra.
ソラの器は小さすぎた。
膨大に膨れ上がったチャクラは 今➡
The massive amount of Chakra
that has gathered up is now
attempting to escape
from Sora's body.
ソラの体から
抜け出そうとしている。
それって…。
That means...
ソラ… その力は…。
Sora... that power...
その力は
お前のためにはならねえ。
That power won't do you any good.
かわりに オレが➡
I will...
オレたち 木ノ葉のみんなが➡
all of us in the Hidden Leaf
will become your...
お前の… お前の力になってやる！
We'll become your power!
Naruto!
ナルト！
(シズネ)綱手様…。
Tsunade-sama...
Shizune! We're going out!
(綱手)シズネ！ 出かけるぞ！
(シズネ)は はい！
Y-Yes, ma'am!
(いの)何これ… これが 九尾!?
What's this...?
Is this the Nine-Tails?
(シカマル)なんてチャクラの量だ。
What an enormous amount of Chakra.
なに!?
What?!
どうしたんでしょう？
なんか 様子がヘンだぜ。
What's happening?
Something's not right.
ヤマト隊長！
Captain Yamato!
Although it has escaped
from Sora's body,
(ヤマト)おそらく ソラの体から
外へ出てみたものの➡
it probably needs a vessel
to maintain its form.
形を保つためには
器が必要なんだろう。
Then...
それじゃあ…。
ソラ…。
Sora!
大丈夫か!? ソラ！
You okay, Sora?!
おい！ 聞こえるか？
Hey! Can you hear me?
起きろよ ソラ！
Wake up, Sora!
ソラ～!!
Sora!
((誰だ…。
Who's there...?
Somebody's calling...
calling me again.
また 誰かが
オレを… オレを呼んでる…。
ソラ！
Sora!
Shut up, Naruto!
(うるせえぞ！ ナルト！))
あ… やっと気がついたか。
Oh, you're finally awake!
ナルト…。
Naruto...
Now, let's go home, Sora.
さぁ 帰ろうぜ ソラ！
帰る？
Go home... Where am I supposed
to go home to?
帰るって いったい
どこに帰るっていうんだよ？
What're you saying?
The Hidden Leaf Village, of course.
何言ってんだよ。
オレたち 木ノ葉の里に
決まってんだろ。
木ノ葉…。
The Hidden Leaf... You mean
the Hidden Leaf I tried to destroy...
オレがつぶそうとした
木ノ葉のことか。
That doesn't matter!
You're our friend!
そんなのは関係ねえ！
お前は オレたちの仲間だ！
It doesn't matter what people say.
We're friends!
誰が何と言おうと どうでもいい。
オレとお前は 仲間だ！
仲間…。
(サクラ)そうよ。
- Friends...
- That's right!
- He looks okay.
- I'm glad...
大丈夫そうですね。
よかった。
(サイ)あのう…。
(サクラ)サイ！
Sai!
Would you guys include me, too?
ボクも まぜてもらっていいかな？
Hell no.
お前は ダメ。
What?! No way.
えっ そんな！
What was so funny
about that just now?
《今のは
何が おかしいのだろう？》
(サクラ)サイ ボケないの。
仲間か…。
Friends, huh...?
Then you're not going back
to the Temple of Fire?
じゃあ 火ノ寺にも
帰らねえのかよ。
Nope.
あぁ。 もっと世界を回って
いろんな人に会ってみたいんだ。
I want to see more of the world
and meet all kinds of people...
And little by little,
I want to make friends like you have.
お前のように 少しずつ
仲間を作っていきたい。
I see...
そっか。
でも たまには寄りなさいよ。
But make sure you stop by
once in a while.
木ノ葉の里は いつでもアンタを
歓迎してあげるから。
The Hidden Leaf Village
will always welcome you...
That's right.
Don't hesitate.
そうだね 気兼ねなく。
ハハハ ありがとよ。
Thanks...
じゃあな。
See you around.
Say "Hi!" to Old Man Asuma for me.
アスマのおっさんに よろしくな。
Sure!
おう！
あぁ そういや 今度こそ お前に➡
Oh... Come to think of it,
next time for sure...
I'll give you a posthumous name.
戒名つけてやっからよ。
You jerk. I just heard that's a name
you give to dead people!
テメエ！ そりゃ
死人につける名前だって➡
さっき聞いたぞ！
(ソラ)ハハッ バ～カ！ 遅えんだよ！
Took you long enough, you idiot.
See you!
じゃあな！
あっ 珍しいっすね
いきなり棒銀なんて。
That's a first for you,
going with a climbing silver
right off the bat.
じっくりやろうぜ
時間もあんだし。
Let's take it nice and slow.
We've got the time, after all.
敵陣突破の先兵だ。
It's an advance guard for
breaking through the enemy's defense.
Sometimes you have to be able
to make moves like this.
たまには こういう指し方も
できないとな。
そういう指し方
嫌いじゃなかったっすか？
I thought you didn't like moves like that.
Just like me.
オレと同じで。
Sacrifice is required in order to protect
the king when your opponent is skilled.
上手相手に 玉を守るためには➡
犠牲もやむなしってヤツだ。
Is something the matter?
なんか あったんすか？
別に… なんにもないよ。
It's nothing...
I just now started to understand
the importance of the "king".
ただ 今ごろになって
玉の大切さが わかってきたのさ。
Well... The game is over if
you get your king taken in Shogi.
そりゃ 玉とられたら
終わりっすからね 将棋は。
If you were to liken the Hidden Leaf Shinobi
to a Shogi piece...
木ノ葉の忍を コマに例えるなら…
シカマル。
Shikamaru...
In the end, you would be a knight.
(アスマ)さしずめ お前は 桂馬だな。
なんで？
Why?
Although weak in strength,
(アスマ)力は弱いが コマを飛び越して
進むことができる。
a knight can advance
by jumping over pieces.
This unique movement resembles
your flexible thinking.
この ユニークな動きは➡
お前の 柔軟な思考に似てる。
Then what would you be?
じゃあ 先生は？
I'm nothing.
I'm just...
オレは 何でもない。 ただの…。
A sacrificial piece... huh?
犠牲ゴマってか。
Then... do you know who the "king" is?
なら 玉は 誰だかわかるか？
The Hokage, right?
(シカマル)火影だろ？
That's what I thought until just recently...
(アスマ)オレも この間までは
そう思ってた。
けど そうじゃなかった。
But it's not like that.
Then who is it?
じゃあ 誰なんすか？
You'll understand when the time comes.
お前も 時が来りゃわかるさ。
You dodge well...
(飛段)よ～くよけるね アンタ。
(飛段)う～ん オレの攻撃スピードは
暁いち のろまでヘタだから➡
My attack speed is the slowest
in the Akatsuki.
I just can't hit anything, can I?
当たりゃしねえ ホント。
I see...
I knew you guys were Akatsuki...
(ユギト)そうか
やはり お前らが 暁か。
(角都)あとは お前だけだ。
You're the only one left.
Well, you're pretty good.
(飛段)いや やるほうだよ アンタさ。
Hey, Hidan.
(角都)おい 飛段。
She's the Two-Tailed Jinchuriki.
You'll die if you get careless.
(角都)コイツは 二尾の人柱力だ。
気を抜くな 死ぬぜ。
Don't give me that, Kakuzu!
それを オレに言うか 角都よ。
I'd like her to kill me anyway.
どうせなら 殺してほしいよ ホント。
Young people
iiijii na riyuu
I'll always accept your excuses
issai yurusu jakuhai
I summoned the rescue team too
resukuyuu tai mo yonde oita
So
dakara
Please kiss me please kiss me
puriizu kisu mii purizu kisu mi
All night
all night
The magic of a fallen angel or the silly pranks of a little demon
datenshi no mahou ka koakuma no chachi na itazura
Before it gets boring
tsuman naku nacchau mae ni
go and hurl
soore de houre
The bowling ball
bouringu booru
It's a strange existence
kibutsuhason zai nado
I know it already
shouchi no suke
It looks breakable...
kowaresou de
Clear the way with those sloppy emotions
tocchirakatta kanjou de kirihirake yo
It looks breakable
kowaresou de
Yet it's not our victory
kowasenai bokura no shouri
Next Episode
Tsunade-sama, the report from Kakashi,
who made contact with
Jiraiya-san, has returned.
Oh, finally. And?
Right. It seems he verified attacks
by what looks like the same pair of Shinobi
in seven locations
in five neighboring lands.
A pair...?
Yes. Although invasion
into the Land of Fire
has not yet been confirmed,
it's only a matter of time...
I see... So they've finally gone
into action, huh?
The Quietly Approaching Threat
Next time: "The Quietly Approaching Threat"